Gustavo Adolfo Toledo Barandica

Neiva-Huila, Colombia

Phone: +57 3183718246

Email: toledo970501@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/gtolbar

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gustavotoledo97/



Professional Profile:

Full Stack Developer, Cloud Developer and Electronics Engineer, certified in AWS cloud practitioner, AWS Technical Essential, CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials, CCNA: Introduction to Networks.

Knowledge and experience of more than 4 years, comprehensive management of technologies such as AWS services, Azure DevOps, Spring Framework, Angular, Kubernetes, SQL, Scrum methodology, performing support, migrations technologies, software architecture, web application design, based on programming processes, project management through the estimation and processing of requirements.

Strong problem-solving skills from results orientation, proactive, continuous support to work teams, investigative capacity, assertive, adaptability to change, focused on meeting goals associated with the IT sector, disciplined and constant.

Professional Experience:

CLOUD DEVELOPER - SOFKA TECHNOLOGIES (August 2024 – Present)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- Developed and implemented a custom resource server with opaque token for Banco General in Panama.
- Migrated API Connect flow to custom applications on Spring framework.
- Developed middleware application for seamless data integration on IBM data bus.
- Developed Infrastructure as Code (IaC) templates using AWS CloudFormation.

Achievements:

- Migration of API Connect to 80% custom applications.
- Connection among APIs 100% with middleware application.
- Coverage greater than 80% of middleware application and resource server

Skills:

Java, Spring boot, Angular, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Junit, Mockito, Jira, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Python.

> JAVA / ANGULAR DEVELOPER - GFT TECHNOLOGIES (January 2023 – August 2024)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- Migrated AWS accounts to a new infrastructure with IaC, integrating resources previously configured manually at Bancolombia.
- Containerized microservices for a white-label project, automating the deployment of the application.
- Support for the bank's applications "Bancolombia" with AWS, Angular Framework, Spring Framework, and others.
- Development of unit tests and mocks for Comfama certificate app.
- Support of bugs for services in the app Cumplimiento for SURA in PL/SQL.

 Service recharge of package is developed for Bancolombia, whose process is the buy of packages of mobile operators in Colombia.

Achievements:

- Migration of AWS infrastructure accounts 100%.
- Coverage greater than 80% of app Confama
- 100% bug fix.
- Bancolombia package service with Puntored from development to production.

Skills:

Java, Spring boot, Angular, AWS, Typescript, Azure DevOps, Oracle DB, Microservices, Time management, PL-SQ, DynamoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, lambdas, PL/SQL, Junit, Mockito.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JVN TECNOLOGIAS (June 2022 – January 2023)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- Upgrade software JDK 1.7 -> 1.8, Oracle WebLogic 10.3.6 -> 14.1.1.0, Oracle coherence -> 14.1.1.0, JSF 1.2 -> JSF 2.x.
- Migrated Database volumes as part of the Oracle Database upgrade.
- Fixing of Bugs in ecommerce web application.

Achievements:

- Successfully achieved 100% upgrade of software modules and fixed compatibility issues with dependencies.
- Migrated 100% of database volumes.
- Achieved compliance metrics for error resolution.

Skills:

Java, AWS, JSF, JIRA, Microservices, Time management, WildFly, jboos, PrimeFaces, PL-SQL, Services Web SOAP, Oracle WebLogic, Bitbucket, Oracle database.

> FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - INGYTAL (May 2022 - August 2022)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

 I worked in the development of a web application for customs control in the Peruvian government, my area of action was in the backend structuring behavior according to the role, in the frontend I worked making screens according to the supplied mockups. The technologies used for the development of this were Spring Framework and Angular implemented under the architecture of microservices and microfrontends.

Achievements:

- Developed and implemented the role-based access control system for the VUCE application using OAuth 2, configuring user permissions to ensure that system resources and functionalities were accessible according to the assigned role, thereby improving the system's security and efficiency.
- Developed and implemented frontend screens for the VUCE application following provided mockups, using Angular. Ensured a consistent and functional user experience, aligned with design and usability requirements.

Skills:

Angular, Spring Boot, AWS, SQL (PostgreSQL), Keycloak, Maven, Gradle, Micro Frontends (single-spa) y Microservices.

> FULLSTACK DEVELOPER - TOLBAR Technology - (January 2022 - April 2022)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

 A - We developed a service to generate certificates using Jasper Report for a client with up-to-date advice. The technologies used for the development of these were Spring Framework and Angular implemented under the layered architecture.

Achievements:

 The company's certificate module is developed and implemented with Jasper Report 100%.

Aptitudes:

Angular, Spring Boot, SQL (MySQL), Jasper Report, Postman, Spring JPA, Spring Security, Services REST, Git

DEVELOPER - Stock Gestión Integral SAS – (February 2017 – February 2018)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

- As a Software and Electronics Developer in the Drone area at StockGI, I played an integral role in the design and development of drone solutions. My responsibilities encompassed:
 - Java Software Development: I designed and programmed software in Java for drone control and monitoring. This included the creation of interfaces and functionalities to manage aspects such as battery, signal, altitude, and other critical parameters.
 - Electronic Hardware Development: I worked on the design of specific electronic components for drones, including printed circuit boards (PCB) and sensors. I ensured the efficiency and reliability of these components.
 - Software and Hardware Integration: I achieved tight integration between software and hardware to ensure smooth operation of the drones.

Achievements:

Application and design for remote parachute launching Drone is developed 100%.

Skills:

Spring Boot, SQL (MySQL), C++, Design 3D, print 3D, Git.

Other work experience:

ACADEMIC MONITOR - Universidad UNAD (June 2020 – December 2021)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

Algebra, Trigonometry and Analytic Geometry Monitor - 2021 General Physics Instructor - 2020

 Provide guidance material to the course and support students with doubts about exact sciences.

Achievements:

 Provide support material for the courses in the areas to be worked on, facilitating a didactic understanding of the course topics.

Skills:

Exact sciences, office automation, leadership, proactivity, knowledge transfer, time management, etc.

BIOMEDICAL TECHNICAL ASSISTANT - EMCOSALUD (August 2014 – January 2016)

AREAS OF EXPERTISE:

Corrective and preventive maintenance of biomedical equipment.

Academic Background:

[ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING], [4.0/5.0]

[Universidad Nacional Abierta y a Distancia - UNAD] [Neiva-Huila, Colombia]

Achievements:

- I became an Academic Monitor in the areas of General Physics and Algebra, Trigonometry and Analytical Geometry for 2 consecutive years.
- 75% scholarship for graduate studies.
- I completed postgraduate studies in Information Technology Management.

[INDUSTRIAL AUTOMATION TECHNOLOGIST], [February 2016]

[Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje - SENA] [Neiva-Huila, Colombia]

Achievements:

 Represent the department of Huila in the Robotics modality in the national WorkSkills of Colombia.

Complementary Training:

- [UPPER INTERMEDIATE LEVEL AT STRIDE] [Present, 2024]
- [INTERMEDIATE LEVEL AT STRIDE] [March, 2023]
- [AWS cloud practioner] [December, 2023]
- [AWS Partner: Acreditación de economía de la nube AWS Entrenamiento de negocios] –
 [December, 2023]
- [AWS Partner: Sales accreditation (Business)] [December, 2023]
- [Design Patterns] [Jun , 2024]
- [RESTful APIs and Microservices] [May , 2024]
- [Intermediate to Advanced Java] [May, 2023]
- [Unit Tests] [May , 2024]
- [Curso de Arquitecturas Limpias para Desarrollo de Software] [September, 2023]
- [Curso de Infraestructura Como Código en AWS] [Jun-2023]
- [Curso Profesional de DevOps] [Feb,2023]
- [Curso de Docker] [Ene-2023]
- [Curso Básico de Jenkins] [Dic-2022]

- [AWS Technical Essential (Spanish)] [April,2022]
- [CCNA: Switching, Routing, and Wireless Essentials] [May, 2022]
- [CCNA Introduction to networks] [May, 2021]

Summary technologies:

- Spring Framework
- Angular
- JAVA
- AWS
- Azure DevOps
- JSF
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle) y PL/SQL
- JIRA
- WebLogic
- Jenkins
- Docker
- Gradle Maven
- GIT (Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket)
- C++ (Microcontrollers)

Other information of interest:

Availability to travel (passport).

Languages:

English: Conversational level

Spanish: Native